- I'm gonna be talking about two courses.
The first is
CS 445
Software Requirement and Specification.
It's the first course of the sequence,
the requirements course,
the three course sequence that teaches
about requirements specification,
implementation testing, enhancement
and management of software.
The first course is CS,
okay, if there's three course sequence,
you can take the same courses
in three different department.
So since its CS, we're
talking about 445 first one.
The next one I'm going
to talk about is 446,
and then someone else I think
is gonna talk about 447.
Next slide.
Okay, this course is about
Requirements Specification.
Requirement are the desired behavior
of systems that you want to build.
Software permanently.
What are we trying to accomplish?
And most importantly,
what does the customer want?
Next.
A specification is the description
of the proposed behavior of a system.
That is the description
of the requirement.
And it has the strength to question that,
"Can we build a software
system that meet our goal?
And what would that do?"
Now, an example of a specification,
we've all had programming assignments
that is specification.
Next.
Now, why an entire
course on specification?
Well, we've learned
that 80 to 85%
of all software errors
that are discovered at any time
during the life of a program,
can be traced back to bad requirement.
And we've also learned that
the cost to fix an error
grows exponentially
with the lifecycle stage.
So if you can fix it
when you're writing the requirement
it might cost maybe a couple of minutes.
By the time you wait
until the software has been delivered,
you're talking about hours and hours,
maybe weeks to fix the same problem,
because of all the other artifacts
that are now connected
to that requirement.
Next.
The course introduces students
to the requirements definition phase
of software development.
It discusses models, notations, processes
for software requirements identification,
representation, analysis
and validating them with the customer.
Now, the course is about how to elicit
discover, invent,
document,
validate, manage
and estimate the cost of requirements
for a computer based system.
Next.
The topics are:
Lifestyle models,
Requirements Modeling,
Requirements Elicitation
Requirements Analysis
Requirements Specifications
and Cost Estimation.
Now,
of course you need to study then
how you evaluate to
and how much work is involved.
40% of the course is
with,
for the course project.
A requirement specification
that you have to write
and to mark the size that leads up to it.
10% is the midterm
and 50% is the final exams
because it's also an engineering course
and they require 50% for final exam.
There are no graduate students here,
so we skip that.
In teams,
you will require
requirements specification
for some medium-sized system
that's the DVD Recorder.
Or this term for example
for by Direct Note Word Parters.
There will be several assignments
that relate to that
and help you get ready to do it
so you don't have to do
it all in the last week.
Okay, next.
The project will allow you
to apply the principles
we're teaching in the class.
Next.
Okay, now, this is
about the second course.
CS 446.
Its title is Software
Design and Architecture
and Project Management.
So it
usually follow Requirement Analysis
in a normal lifecycle.
So that impact can follow.
Okay, so this course has three names
depending on which department you're in.
We're in CS so we'll talk 446.
Next.
The course introduces
students to the design,
implementation and evaluation phases
of software development.
It discusses software development,
design processes,
methods, the notations,
for implementation of design,
evolution of design
and implementation
and the management of
all of these activities.
So the topics are:
Lifecycle models again,
always apply to this phase.
Modularity,
Architecture,
Design Notation and Processes,
Management and Cost Estimation
based on design rather than requirement
and Risk Management,
trying to prevent all those things
that could go wrong from killing you,
Implementation,
Integration and Configuration Management,
Evolution, Maintenance and Enhancement.
Okay.
Thank you.
Are there any questions about it?
In case you're worried,
all of these courses
have a heavy workload.
So don't be surprised.
But, you're gonna have fun.
Okay, because your TA's
and your professors
will be your customers.